

Denver, CO = RyanGarofalo100@gmail.com = RyanGarofalo.com = (518) 307-6826 = Ryan-Garofalo = The RyanGarofalo1

# **PROJECTS**

#### **Bet Your Spots**

A fantasy sports web application that allows users to gamble bogus money based on actual games and spreads, providing an exciting gaming experience for users. The application utilizes the Fantasy Datas API to generate details from a random 2008–2015 NFL game. Bet Your Sports was built with JavaScript, JQuery, with custom CSS.

#### Flake

Flake is a social networking application designed to increase productivity and reducing flaking. It is a decoupled app the utilizes React.js, Node.js, Express, PostgreSQL, Bootstrap and custom CSS

#### **Pokemon Node**

A web application that allows users to keep track of their favorite Pokemon and send them to the gym for battle. Pokemon Node is a CRUD app written with Node.js, Express, PostgreSQL, with a JavaScript, custom CSS, and Bootstrap frontend.

#### Mean Ski

Mean Ski is an e-commerce storefront that allows users to view items and add them to a shopping cart. This project utilizes AngularJS and demonstrates the power of two-way data binding. Other technologies used include Bootstrap, JavaScript, and custom CSS.

# **EXPERIENCE**

### Signpost

February 2015 - February 2016

### **Senior Sales Executive**

Sold Signpost CRM platform to merchants from all types of small to medium sized businesses. Utilized Salesforce to effectively manage sales pipeline and keep a steady deal flow. Broke sales in a month record. Top team 4 times in company and 4 time top tier sales representative recognition.

### Glens Falls Produce October 2011 - January 2015

### **Account Manager**

Managed 100+ accounts using new proprietary software. Focused on increasing efficiency in warehouse operations, upselling, and customer retention. Created and managed website content and social media. Streamlined sales process with computer network and custom software.

## **EDUCATION**

Galvanize Denver May 2016 - Oct 2016

### Web Development Immersive

Intensive 6-month full time software development program. 1000+ hours of coding. Focused on JavaScript, Node.js, Express, AngularJS and PostgreSQL

SUNY Plattsburgh

Major: Psychology, Minor: Business

Honors: Psi Chi National Psychology Honor Society Study Abroad Program: Bond University, Gold Coast Australia

# **SKILLS**

JAVASCRIPT	REACTJS	AJAX	CLI/UNIX	PIVOTAL TRACKER	KNEX.JS
HTML5	ANGULARJS	GIT/GITHUB	FIREBASE	SALESFORCE	AGILE DEVELOPMENT
CSS3	EXPRESS	BOOTSTRAP	HEROKU	POSTGRESQL	PAIR PROGRAMMING
SQL	NODE.JS	JQUERY	API INTEGRATION	JADE	MOCHA/CHAI